Nicholas Malone

Portfolio: people.rit.edu/nmm3037/portfolio/ Phone: (508)-245-6363

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/nicholas-malone4/
Email: nicholasmalone01400@yahoo.com

OBJECTIVE:

To work on big gaming projects that can be played and seen by millions of players. Create exciting and unique gameplay in multiplayer environments. Use years of level design and playtest organizing experience to perfect any product being released to the public.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science, Game Design & Development, Minor in Software Engineering Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT), Rochester NY

Dec 2023 **GPA: 3.72**

Skills Summary:

Languages: C#, C/C++, HTML5, CSS, React, JavaScript, Java, XML, PHP

Tools: Visual Studio/Code, Git, Unity, Unreal Engine, Hammer++, Maya, Photoshop, Illustrator, Trello, Slack

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Rochester Institute of Technology

Teaching Assistant (Level Design)

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Rochester, NY

- Graded assignments for 60+ Level Design students over the course of a semester
- Gave constructive criticism and feedback to students as their projects came along and when finished

Super League Gaming (Minehut)

Jan 2022- Aug 2022

Level Designer (Contract)

Remote

Remote

- Designed multiplayer levels for teams of streamers to play in Twitch Rivals events
- Conducted playtests and integrated community feedback during beta tests
- Regularly communicated with developers during gamemode prototyping to ensure a polished product

Turtle Entertainment (ESL Gaming)

Jan 2017 - June 2018

Level Designer

- Created multiplayer levels for a competitive environment
- Managed a community of competitive teams and players
- Conducted playtests and integrated community feedback into future updates
- Regularly communicated with developers during gamemode prototyping to ensure a polished product

PROJECTS:

Overcast Community

Dec 2019 - Present

Lead Level Designer & Community Manager

Remote

- Organize tournaments and map competitions to increase community interaction
- Manage a repository of over 1500 levels with map pool updates every month for more variety to the players
- Lead a group of builders on new game modes and projects to complete within set deadlines
- Create new competitive maps for tournaments and ranked play